const politics = [
    {
        number: "1",
        question: "Which state was George W Bush governor of before becoming President of the United States?",
        answer: "texas",
        hint: "The second largest US state"
    },
    {
        number: "2",
        question: "Which former British Prime Minister graduated from Oxford University in 1947 with Second-Class Honours in Chemistry?",
        answer: "margaret thatcher",
        hint: "Known as the iron-lady"
    },
    {
        number: "3",
        question: "How long does Prime Minister’s Questions last?",
        answer: "thirty minutes",
        hint: "Less that three quarters of an hour but more than fifteen minutes"
    },
    {
        number: "4",
        question: "A member of which band threw a bucket of water over John Prescott at the 1998 Brit Awards?",
        answer: "chumbawamba",
        hint: "The lead singer was Dunstan Bruce"
    },
    {
        number: "5",
        question: "What did Theresa May claim was the naughtiest thing she had done as a child in a 2017 interview?",
        answer: "ran through fields of wheat",
        hint: "Farmers would not be best pleased"
    },
    {
        number: "6",
        question: "Which politician described Russia as “a riddle, wrapped in a mystery, inside an enigma”?",
        answer: "winston Churchill",
        hint: "Statue stands directly outside The Palace of Westminster"
    },
    {
        number: "7",
        question: "What is the name of the gallery for members of the public to watch The House of Commons?",
        answer: "strangers’ gallery",
        hint: "Located above the Commons"
    },
    {
        number: "8",
        question: "What is the official name of Big Ben?",
        answer: "elizabeth tower",
        hint: "It was renamed for the Queens diamond jubliee"
    },
    {
        number: "9",
        question: "What animal is the symbol of the US Democratic Party?",
        answer: "donkey",
        hint: "A common farm yard animal"
    },
    {
        number: "10",
        question: "Who is the current King of Jordan?",
        answer: "abdullah II",
        hint: "In 1980 he graduated from the Royal Military Academy in Sandhurst"
    },
    {
        number: "11",
        question: "Where did Richard Nixon hold his famous “I’m Not a Crook” press conference?",
        answer: "disney world",
        hint: "Perhaps Mickey mouse was watching?"
    },
    {
        number: "12",
        question: "Who was the only British Prime Minister to be assassinated?",
        answer: "spencer perceval",
        hint: "Born November 1762"
    },
    {
        number: "13",
        question: "Which US President was diagnosed with polio after becoming paralysed from the waist down?",
        answer: "franklin d. roosevelt",
        hint: "Often referred to as FDR"
    },
    {
        number: "14",
        question: "What were French Fries renamed to in several US Congressional cafeterias after France refused to support the Iraq War?",
        answer: "freedom fries",
        hint: "*Similar to liberty* - fries"
    },
    {
        number: "15",
        question: "Former leader of Change UK Anna Soubry used to be a presenter on which long-running daytime show?",
        answer: "this morning",
        hint: "Currently being presented by Holly Willoughby"
    },
    {
        number: "16",
        question: "True or false: in 2002 the President of Turkmenistan renamed the month of January after himself",
        answer: "true",
        hint: "January would now be called 'Turkmenbashi'"
    },
    {
        number: "17",
        question: "During the State Opening of Parliament, the doors of the House of Lords are shut in front of Black Rod – what historical event does this ritual date back to?",
        answer: "english civil war",
        hint: "From 22 August 1642 - 3 September 1651"
    },
    {
        number: "18",
        question: "“If you let a bully come into your front yard, the next day he’ll be on your porch” is a quote from which US President?",
        answer: "lyndon b. johnson",
        hint: "Ofton referred to as LBJ"
    },
    {
        number: "19",
        question: "How long is a French President elected for?",
        answer: "five years",
        hint: "Between three and 6 years"
    },
    {
        number: "20",
        question: "Which Conservative politician famously fed British beef to his daughter, in a press event to prove its safety from B.S.E?",
        answer: "john gummer",
        hint: "Brother of Peter Gummer, Baron Chadlington"
    }

];

export default politics;
